<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>concepts on</title><link>https://libremfg.github.io/categories/concepts/</link><description>Recent content in concepts on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 19:39:39 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://libremfg.github.io/categories/concepts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What is Rhize?</title><link>https://libremfg.github.io/get-started/introduction/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 12:25:46 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://libremfg.github.io/get-started/introduction/</guid><description>Rhize is a real-time, event-driven manufacturing data hub. It unites data analysis, event monitoring, and process execution in one platform. Its interface and architecture is designed to conform to your processes. We assume nothing about what your manufacturing workflows look like.
Rhize has only one strong opinion: all data exchanged must be modeled on the ISA-95 standard. This standards-based schema is how Rhize connects every data event across an entire operation.</description></item><item><title>Operations Events</title><link>https://libremfg.github.io/concepts/isa95/operationsevents/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://libremfg.github.io/concepts/isa95/operationsevents/</guid><description>EDA is designed to address various business problems by providing a scalable, flexible, and responsive approach to handling events and data flow. Some of the key business problems that EDA helps to solve include:
Real-time Responsiveness: EDA enables businesses to respond to events and changes in real-time. It ensures that critical information is processed and acted upon immediately, allowing organizations to make timely decisions and take appropriate actions.
Decoupling of Systems: In traditional architectures, systems are often tightly coupled, making it challenging to introduce changes or new functionalities without affecting other parts of the system.</description></item><item><title>Overview</title><link>https://libremfg.github.io/concepts/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://libremfg.github.io/concepts/overview/</guid><description>Rhize is a real-time, Event-driven, Manufacturing Data Hub that has built-in Business Process Orchestration.
So what&amp;rsquo;s all that then?
Challenges For manufacturers, digitalization can bring numerous benefits, including increased productivity, improved efficiency, and enhanced decision-making capabilities. However, successful implementation must overcome many challenges:
Legacy Systems and Infrastructure: Many manufacturing facilities have outdated systems and equipment that may not be compatible with digital technologies. Integrating new digital solutions with existing infrastructure can be complex and require significant investments to upgrade or replace outdated systems.</description></item><item><title>Realtime Database</title><link>https://libremfg.github.io/concepts/architecture/realtime-database/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://libremfg.github.io/concepts/architecture/realtime-database/</guid><description>A real-time database is a type of database system that is designed to handle and process data in real-time or near real-time, meaning that data changes are immediately reflected and accessible to users or applications without any noticeable delay. These databases are commonly used in scenarios where data needs to be continuously updated and retrieved in a highly responsive manner.
Traditional databases, such as relational databases, are optimized for handling transactions and data consistency but may not be as efficient for real-time applications.</description></item><item><title>Data Hub Architecture</title><link>https://libremfg.github.io/concepts/architecture/data-hub/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://libremfg.github.io/concepts/architecture/data-hub/</guid><description>A data hub architecture is a centralized platform or infrastructure that serves as a hub for collecting, integrating, storing, and processing data from various sources within an organization. It provides a unified view of data and enables seamless data sharing and analysis across different systems and applications. In the context of manufacturing digitalization, a data hub architecture can help address several challenges:
Data Integration: Manufacturing facilities generate data from various sources, such as production equipment, sensors, supply chain systems, and quality control processes.</description></item><item><title>Event Driven Architecture</title><link>https://libremfg.github.io/concepts/architecture/eda/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://libremfg.github.io/concepts/architecture/eda/</guid><description>Event-driven architecture (EDA) is a software design pattern that focuses on the flow of events, notifications, and messages within a system to facilitate communication and interaction between different components or services. In EDA, systems are built to respond to events rather than following a strict procedural flow.
At the heart of is the concept of events. Events are discrete occurrences or notifications that represent changes or actions within a system. These events can include user actions, changes in data, external triggers, or any other meaningful incident.</description></item><item><title>Business Process Orchestration</title><link>https://libremfg.github.io/concepts/architecture/business-process-orchestration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://libremfg.github.io/concepts/architecture/business-process-orchestration/</guid><description>Event orchestration is the coordination and management of various events, actions, and processes within a system or across multiple systems. It involves arranging and controlling the sequence of events to ensure that they occur in a logical and efficient manner, often to achieve a specific goal or outcome. Event orchestration is commonly used in various domains, including IT operations, business processes, and even in the context of cloud computing and automation.</description></item><item><title>How Rhize works</title><link>https://libremfg.github.io/get-started/how-rhize-works/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 19:39:39 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://libremfg.github.io/get-started/how-rhize-works/</guid><description>This article provides a high-level overview of how Rhize works, starting with data collection and ending with user interaction. To make these concepts more concrete, the final section provides examples of each process.
The heart of the Rhize platform is its manufacturing knowledge graph, which stores data from all levels of the operation and exposes this data through a single endpoint. Around the database are services that exchange messages and process events in real-time.</description></item><item><title>Concepts</title><link>https://libremfg.github.io/concepts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 19:35:35 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://libremfg.github.io/concepts/</guid><description/></item><item><title>BPMN execution recovery</title><link>https://libremfg.github.io/deploy/restore/bpmn-nodes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://libremfg.github.io/deploy/restore/bpmn-nodes/</guid><description>BPMN processes often have longer execution durations and many steps. If a BPMN node suddenly fails (for example through a panic or loss of power), Rhize needs to ensure that the workflow completes.
To achieve high availability and resiliency, Rhize services run in Kubernetes nodes, and the NATS message broker typically has data replication. As long as the remaining BPMN nodes are not already at full processing capacity, if a BPMN node fails while executing a process, the Rhize system recovers and finishes the workflow.</description></item><item><title>About OpenID connect</title><link>https://libremfg.github.io/deploy/about-openidconnect/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://libremfg.github.io/deploy/about-openidconnect/</guid><description>Rhize uses OpenIDConnect to connect to a Keycloak server to authenticate users and manage Role-based access controls.
Open ID Connect is a security architecture that uses JSON Web Tokens (JWTs) to access secured resources. JWTs are issued by KeyCloak. Users can also be managed in KeyCloak. Or you can manage users in other services such as LDAP, Google, Azure AD, Facebook, etc.
The general authentication flow is as follows:
When a user accesses the user interface, the UI redirects to Keycloak.</description></item><item><title>ISA 95</title><link>https://libremfg.github.io/concepts/isa95/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 19:35:35 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://libremfg.github.io/concepts/isa95/</guid><description>Overview</description></item><item><title>Architecture</title><link>https://libremfg.github.io/concepts/architecture/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://libremfg.github.io/concepts/architecture/</guid><description/></item><item><title>DataHub</title><link>https://libremfg.github.io/concepts/datahub/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://libremfg.github.io/concepts/datahub/</guid><description> Dgraph is the native GraphQL database with a graph backend. It is open-source, scalable, distributed, highly available and lightning fast. Overview A guide to streaming data from OPCUA into the RHIZE MFG Data Hub Streaming Data A guide to streaming data from OPCUA into the RHIZE MFG Data Hub</description></item><item><title>Overview</title><link>https://libremfg.github.io/concepts/datahub/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://libremfg.github.io/concepts/datahub/overview/</guid><description>Multi-site manufacturing businesses have a data governance problem.
If they implement data governance centrally, it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to get the people at each site aligned and in agreement. This leads to centrally governed reports that site personnel don&amp;rsquo;t use or, worse, are inaccurate.
If they implement data governance at the site level, it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to align data centrally to enable applications and analytics to be built once and deployed many times across sites.</description></item></channel></rss>