<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Architecture on</title><link>/concepts/architecture/</link><description>Recent content in Architecture on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/concepts/architecture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Realtime Database</title><link>/concepts/architecture/realtime-database/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/concepts/architecture/realtime-database/</guid><description>Overview What is a Real-time Database? A real-time database is a type of database system that is designed to handle and process data in real-time or near real-time, meaning that data changes are immediately reflected and accessible to users or applications without any noticeable delay. These databases are commonly used in scenarios where data needs to be continuously updated and retrieved in a highly responsive manner.
Traditional databases, such as relational databases, are optimized for handling transactions and data consistency but may not be as efficient for real-time applications.</description></item><item><title>Data Hub Architecture</title><link>/concepts/architecture/data-hub/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/concepts/architecture/data-hub/</guid><description>What is a Data Hub Architecture? A data hub architecture is a centralized platform or infrastructure that serves as a hub for collecting, integrating, storing, and processing data from various sources within an organization. It provides a unified view of data and enables seamless data sharing and analysis across different systems and applications. In the context of manufacturing digitalization, a data hub architecture can help address several challenges:
Data Integration: Manufacturing facilities generate data from various sources, such as production equipment, sensors, supply chain systems, and quality control processes.</description></item><item><title>Event Driven Architecture</title><link>/concepts/architecture/eda/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/concepts/architecture/eda/</guid><description>Overview What is Event Driven Architecture? Event-Driven Architecture (EDA) is a software design pattern that focuses on the flow of events, notifications, and messages within a system to facilitate communication and interaction between different components or services. In an event-driven architecture, systems are built to respond to events rather than following a strict procedural flow.
At the heart of EDA is the concept of events. Events are discrete occurrences or notifications that represent changes or actions within a system.</description></item><item><title>Business Process Orchestration</title><link>/concepts/architecture/business-process-orchestration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/concepts/architecture/business-process-orchestration/</guid><description>Overview Event orchestration refers to the coordination and management of various events, actions, and processes within a system or across multiple systems. It involves arranging and controlling the sequence of events to ensure that they occur in a logical and efficient manner, often to achieve a specific goal or outcome. Event orchestration is commonly used in various domains, including IT operations, business processes, and even in the context of cloud computing and automation.</description></item></channel></rss>