<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Restore on</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/restore/</link><description>Recent content in Restore on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 19:35:35 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/restore/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Restore the GraphDB</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/restore/graphdb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 13:52:23 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/restore/graphdb/</guid><description>This guide shows you how to restore the Graph database in your Rhize environment.
Prerequisites Before you start, ensure you have the following:
The GraphDB Helm chart kubectl A Database backup Steps Confirm the cluster and namespace are correct.
## context kubectl config current-context ## namespace kubectl get namespace To change the namespace for all subsequent kubectl commands to libre, run this command:
kubectl config set-context --current --namespace=libre For a reference of useful kubectl commands, refer to the official kubectl Cheat Sheet.</description></item><item><title>Restore Keycloak</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/restore/keycloak/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 13:26:23 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/restore/keycloak/</guid><description>This guide shows you how to restore Keycloak in your Rhize environment.
Caution Restoring Keycloak to an existing running instance will involve downtime.
The expected downtime for an existing running instance depends on the cluster performance sizing, backup size and bandwidth speed to the Kubernetes cluster. Downtime is typically under a minute.
Prerequisites Before you start, ensure you have the following:
kubectl A Keycloak backup Steps Confirm the cluster and namespace are correct:</description></item><item><title>Restore Grafana</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/restore/grafana/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 13:52:23 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/restore/grafana/</guid><description>This guide shows you how to restore Grafana in your Rhize environment.
Prerequisites Before you start, ensure you have the following:
kubectl A Grafana backup Steps Confirm the cluster and namespace are correct:
## context kubectl config current-context ## namespace kubectl get namespace To change the namespace for all subsequent kubectl commands to libre, run this command:
kubectl config set-context --current --namespace=libre For a reference of useful kubectl commands, refer to the official kubectl Cheat Sheet.</description></item><item><title>BPMN execution recovery</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/restore/bpmn-nodes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/restore/bpmn-nodes/</guid><description>BPMN processes often have longer execution durations and many steps. If a BPMN node suddenly fails (for example through a panic or loss of power), Rhize needs to ensure that the workflow completes.
To achieve high availability and resiliency, Rhize services run in Kubernetes nodes, and the NATS message broker typically has data replication. As long as the remaining BPMN nodes are not already at full processing capacity, if a BPMN node fails while executing a process, the Rhize system recovers and finishes the workflow.</description></item></channel></rss>