<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Reference on</title><link>https://libremfg.github.io/reference/</link><description>Recent content in Reference on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 16:49:42 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://libremfg.github.io/reference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>GraphQL Directives</title><link>https://libremfg.github.io/reference/directives/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://libremfg.github.io/reference/directives/</guid><description>The list of all directives supported by Rhize&amp;rsquo;s implementation of Dgraph.
@auth @auth allows you to define how to apply authorization rules on the queries/mutation for a type.
Reference: Auth directive
@cascade @cascade allows you to filter out certain nodes within a query.
Reference: Cascade
@custom @custom directive is used to define custom queries, mutations and fields.
Reference: Custom directive
@default The @default directive allows you to specify values that should be used when nil values are received for either add mutations or update mutations</description></item><item><title>Default local ports</title><link>https://libremfg.github.io/reference/default-ports/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 16:49:42 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://libremfg.github.io/reference/default-ports/</guid><description>After you install Rhize services, they are accessible, by default, on the following ports:
Service Default Port Admin UI localhost:3030 Grafana localhost:3001 Router localhost:4000 Keycloak localhost:8090 baas-alpha command line localhost:8080</description></item><item><title>Agent configuration</title><link>https://libremfg.github.io/reference/agent-configuration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://libremfg.github.io/reference/agent-configuration/</guid><description>The Rhize agent collects data that is emitted in the manufacturing process and makes this data visible in the Rhize system. It works by connecting to equipment or groups of equipment that run over protocols such as OPC UA.
As the communication bridge between the Rhize Data Hub and your plant, the agent has multiple functions:
It subscribes to tags and republishes the changes in NATS. It creates an interface for the BPMN engine to send reads and writes to a data source and its associated equipment.</description></item><item><title>Glossary</title><link>https://libremfg.github.io/reference/glossary/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 19:35:35 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://libremfg.github.io/reference/glossary/</guid><description>The manufacturing industry has many specialized terms—and many abbreviations. This glossary is a reference of how Rhize defines terms used in this documentation.
Agent The Rhize agent bridges your plant processes with the Rhize data hub. It collects data that is emitted during the manufacturing process and publishes it to the NATS message broker. Andon A system that alerts manufacturing teams about problems in processes or quality. Business Process Model and Notation (BPMN) A standardized graphical notation used to represent business processes in an intuitive, visual way.</description></item></channel></rss>