<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Back up on Rhize documentation</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/backup/</link><description>Recent content in Back up on Rhize documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 11:20:56 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/backup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Back up the Graph DB</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/backup/graphdb/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 11:01:46 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/backup/graphdb/</guid><description>This guide shows you how to back up the Rhize Graph database. You can also use it to model an automation workflow.
Prerequisites Before you start, ensure you have the following:
A designated backup location, for example ~/rhize-backups/database. Access to your Rhize Kubernetes Environment Optional: kubectx utilities kubectx to manage multiple clusters kubens to switch between and configure namespaces easily Optional: the k8 Lens IDE, if you prefer to use Kubernetes graphically.</description></item><item><title>Back up Audit PostgreSQL</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/backup/audit/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 11:20:56 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/backup/audit/</guid><description>This guide shows you the procedure to backup your Audit PostgreSQL database on your Rhize Kubernetes deployment.
Prerequisites Before you start, ensure you have the following:
A designated backup location, for example ~/rhize-backups/libre-audit. Access to the Rhize Kubernetes Environment Optional: kubectx utilities kubectx to manage multiple clusters kubens to switch between and configure namespaces easily Optional: the k8 Lens IDE, if you prefer to use Kubernetes graphically Also, before you start, confirm you are in the right context and namespace.</description></item><item><title>Back up Keycloak</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/backup/keycloak/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 14:30:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/backup/keycloak/</guid><description>This guide shows you how to back up Keycloak on your Rhize Kubernetes deployment.
Prerequisites Before you start, ensure you have the following:
A designated backup location, for example ~/rhize-backups/keycloak. Access to the Rhize Kubernetes Environment Optional: kubectx utilities kubectx to manage multiple clusters kubens to switch between and configure namespaces easily Optional: the k8 Lens IDE, if you prefer to use Kubernetes graphically Also, before you start, confirm you are in the right context and namespace.</description></item><item><title>Back up Grafana</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/backup/grafana/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 11:01:56 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/backup/grafana/</guid><description>This guide shows you the procedure to back up Grafana on your Rhize Kubernetes deployment. For general instructions, refer to the official Back up Grafana documentation.
Prerequisites Before you start, ensure you have the following:
A designated backup location, for example ~/rhize-backups/grafana. Access to the Rhize Kubernetes Environment Optional: kubectx utilities kubectx to manage multiple clusters kubens to switch between and configure namespaces easily Optional: the k8 Lens IDE, if you prefer to use Kubernetes graphically Also, before you start, confirm you are in the right context and namespace.</description></item></channel></rss>