<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Reference on Rhize documentation</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/categories/reference/</link><description>Recent content in Reference on Rhize documentation</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 16:29:21 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.rhize.com/categories/reference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Master definitions and fields</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/model/master-definitions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 16:29:21 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/model/master-definitions/</guid><description>To make a production object visible to the Rhize data hub, you must define it as a data model.
These sections document all the objects that you can add through the UI, and the fields and properties that you can associate with them. All these models are based on the ISA-95 standard, mostly from Part 2, which describes the role-based equipment hierarchy.
Note For visual examples of how some of these models relate, look at our page of ISA-95 Diagrams.</description></item><item><title>Default URLs and local ports</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/reference/default-ports/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 16:49:42 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/reference/default-ports/</guid><description>After you install Rhize services, they are accessible, by default, on the following ports:
Service Default Port Admin UI localhost:3030 Grafana localhost:3001 Router localhost:4000 Keycloak localhost:8090 baas-alpha command line localhost:8080 URLs When you create DNS records, Rhize recommends the following URLs:
Service Domain Admin UI rhize-ui.&amp;lt;YOUR_DOMAIN&amp;gt; Keycloak rhize-auth.&amp;lt;YOUR_DOMAIN&amp;gt; GraphQL rhize-api.&amp;lt;YOUR_DOMAIN&amp;gt; NATS rhize-mqtt.&amp;lt;YOUR_DOMAIN&amp;gt; Grafana rhize-grafana.&amp;lt;YOUR_DOMAIN&amp;gt;</description></item><item><title>Agent configuration</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/reference/service-config/agent-configuration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/reference/service-config/agent-configuration/</guid><description>The Rhize agent collects data that is emitted in the manufacturing process and makes this data visible in the Rhize system. It works by connecting to equipment or groups of equipment that run over protocols such as OPC UA.
As the communication bridge between the Rhize Data Hub and your plant, the agent has multiple functions:
It subscribes to tags and republishes the changes in NATS. It creates an interface for the BPMN engine to send reads and writes to a data source and its associated equipment.</description></item><item><title>Audit configuration</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/reference/service-config/audit-configuration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/reference/service-config/audit-configuration/</guid><description>Audit offers a secure and unchangeable record of all activities that happen within the Rhize system.
logging Logs the configuration to the console.
Attributes Description type Specifies the logging configuration type: json, multi, or console. (Default: console) Level Configures the level of logging: Trace, Debug, Info, Warn, Error, Fatal, and Panic. (Default: Trace) OIDC Configurations for Keycloak authentication and connection with OpenID Connect.
Attributes Description serverUrl The URL of the OpenID Connect server.</description></item><item><title>BPMN configuration</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/reference/service-config/bpmn-configuration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/reference/service-config/bpmn-configuration/</guid><description>The Rhize BPMN acts as the tailored engine for processing low-code workflows designed within the [BPMN UI]/how-to/bpmn/. The configurations manage the connection and data flow on the BPMN engine to the other Rhize microservices.
http All HTTP configurations are measured in seconds.
Attribute Description ReadHeaderTimeout Wait duration for the request header to be fully read before timing out. (Default: 10) ReadTimeout Wait duration for the entire request to be read before timing out.</description></item><item><title>Calendar Service configuration</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/reference/service-config/calendar-configuration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/reference/service-config/calendar-configuration/</guid><description>The Calendar Service handles polling work calendar definitions and generating work calendar entries in the graph and time series databases.
logging Logs the configuration to the console.
Attributes Description type Specifies the logging configuration type: json, multi, or console. (Default: console) Level Configures the level of logging: Trace, Debug, Info, Warn, Error, Fatal, and Panic. (Default: Trace) NATS Message broker that drives Rhize&amp;rsquo;s event-based architecture.
Attributes Description SERVER_URL The URL of the NATS server.</description></item><item><title>Core configuration</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/reference/service-config/core-configuration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/reference/service-config/core-configuration/</guid><description>The Core service oversees data sources such as OPC-UA servers and manages the publication and subscription of topics within the NATS messaging system.
logging Logs the configuration to the console.
Attributes Description type Specifies the logging configuration type: json, multi, or console. (Default: console) Level Configures the level of logging: Trace, Debug, Info, Warn, Error, Fatal, and Panic. (Default: Trace) NATS Message broker that drives Rhize&amp;rsquo;s event-based architecture.
Attributes Description serverUrl The URL of the NATS server.</description></item><item><title>Special variables</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/bpmn/variables/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/bpmn/variables/</guid><description>Rhize designates some variable names for a special purpose in BPMN workflow. This list these special variables is as follows:
Variable Purpose BODY The name of the variable as Input in Intermediate message throws. The value of this variable is the payload sent to the Rhize message broker. customResponse A value to report at the end of a synchronous API call to trigger a workflow. On completion, the call reports whatever the value was in the customResponse field of the GraphQL response.</description></item><item><title>GraphQL types and filters</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/reference/gql-types/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/reference/gql-types/</guid><description>This page provides a reference of the data types enforced by the Rhize database schema, and of the filters that can apply to these types when you query, update, or delete a set of resources. For an extended guide, with examples, read Use query filters.
Note These filters are based on Rhize&amp;rsquo;s implementation of the Dgraph @search directives. Data types Every object in the Rhize schema has fields that are of one of the basic data types.</description></item><item><title>Glossary</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/reference/glossary/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 19:35:35 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/reference/glossary/</guid><description>The manufacturing industry has many specialized terms—and many abbreviations. This glossary is a reference of how Rhize defines terms used in this documentation.
Agent The Rhize agent bridges your plant processes with the Rhize data hub. It collects data that is emitted during the manufacturing process and publishes it to the NATS message broker.Andon A system that alerts manufacturing teams about problems in processes or quality.Audit The Libre Audit log server is a service that provides a tamper-proof and immutable audit trail of all events that occur in the Rhize system.</description></item><item><title>Naming conventions</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/bpmn/naming-conventions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/bpmn/naming-conventions/</guid><description>Note These are recommendations. Your organization may adapt the conventions to its needs. Each BPMN workflow has an ID, as does each node in the workflow. Rhize recommends adopting a set of conventions about how you name these elements. Standardizing BPMN names across an environment has multiple benefits:
Consistent workflow naming conventions help you filter and find workflows in the process list. Well-named nodes make the workflow behavior easier to understand at a glance.</description></item><item><title>BPMN learning resources</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/bpmn/learning-resources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/bpmn/learning-resources/</guid><description>Here are some links to supplemental tools and material to help you build BPMN workflows in Rhize:
BPMN templates. A repository of BPMN workflows that you can download and run yourself. bpmn.io. Opensourcing rendering toolkits and editors for BPMN 2.0. You can use the bpmn-js for local, offline building. Rhize Youtube channel. Includes demos of BPMN. 📝 OMG BPMN standard. The standard on which the Rhize BPMN engine and UI is based.</description></item><item><title>BMPN elements</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/bpmn/bpmn-elements/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 11:10:37 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/bpmn/bpmn-elements/</guid><description>This document describes the parameters available to each BPMN element in the Rhize UI. These parameters control how users set conditions, transform data, access variables, call services, and so on.
Common parameters Every BPMN workflow and every element that the workflow contains have the following parameters:
Parameter Description ID Mandatory unique ID. For guidance, follow the BPMN naming conventions. Name Optional human readable name. If empty, takes ID value. Documentation Optional freeform text for additional information Extension properties Optional metadata to add to workflow or node Events Events are something that happen in the course of a process.</description></item></channel></rss>