<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Reference on Rhize documentation</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/categories/reference/</link><description>Recent content in Reference on Rhize documentation</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 16:29:21 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.rhize.com/categories/reference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Master definitions and fields</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/model/master-definitions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 16:29:21 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/model/master-definitions/</guid><description>To make a production object visible to the Rhize data hub, you must define it as a data model.
These sections document all the objects that you can add through the UI, and the fields and properties that you can associate with them. All these models are based on the ISA-95 standard, mostly from Part 2, which describes the role-based equipment hierarchy.
Global object fields All objects that you define must have a unique name.</description></item><item><title>Default URLs and local ports</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/reference/default-ports/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 16:49:42 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/reference/default-ports/</guid><description>After you install Rhize services, they are accessible, by default, on the following ports:
Service Default Port Admin UI localhost:3030 Grafana localhost:3001 Router localhost:4000 Keycloak localhost:8090 baas-alpha command line localhost:8080 URLs When you create DNS records, Rhize recommends the following URLs:
Service Domain Admin UI rhize-ui.&amp;lt;YOUR_DOMAIN&amp;gt; Keycloak rhize-auth.&amp;lt;YOUR_DOMAIN&amp;gt; GraphQL rhize-api.&amp;lt;YOUR_DOMAIN&amp;gt; NATS rhize-mqtt.&amp;lt;YOUR_DOMAIN&amp;gt; Grafana rhize-grafana.&amp;lt;YOUR_DOMAIN&amp;gt;</description></item><item><title>Agent configuration</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/reference/agent-configuration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/reference/agent-configuration/</guid><description>The Rhize agent collects data that is emitted in the manufacturing process and makes this data visible in the Rhize system. It works by connecting to equipment or groups of equipment that run over protocols such as OPC UA.
As the communication bridge between the Rhize Data Hub and your plant, the agent has multiple functions:
It subscribes to tags and republishes the changes in NATS. It creates an interface for the BPMN engine to send reads and writes to a data source and its associated equipment.</description></item><item><title>Audit configuration</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/reference/audit-configuration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/reference/audit-configuration/</guid><description>Audit offers a secure and unchangeable record of all activities taking place within the Rhize system. When changing configuration options, see here for details:
logging Logs the configuration to the console.
Attributes Description type Specifies the logging configuration type: json, multi, or console by default. (Default: console) Level Configures the level of logging: Trace, Debug, Info, Warn, Error, Fatal, and Panic. (Default: Trace) OIDC Configurations for Keycloak authentication and connection with OpenID Connect.</description></item><item><title>BPMN configuration</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/reference/bpmn-configuration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/reference/bpmn-configuration/</guid><description>[BPMN Overview]
[BPMN Functions]
http All HTTP configurations are measured in seconds.
Attribute Description ReadHeaderTimeout Wait duration for the request header to be fully read before timing out. (Default: 10) ReadTimeout Wait duration for the entire request to be read before timing out. (Default: 15) WriteTimeout Wait duration for the entire response to be written before timing out. (Default: 10) IdleTimeout Wait duration for the next request whil the connection is idle before timing out.</description></item><item><title>Core configuration</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/reference/core-configuration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/reference/core-configuration/</guid><description>Core acts as a bespoke edge agent, overseeing data sources such as OPC-UA servers, and managing the publication and subscription of topics within the NATS messaging system.
logging Logs the configuration to the console.
Attributes Description type Specifies the logging configuration type: json, multi, or console by default. (Default: console) Level Configures the level of logging: Trace, Debug, Info, Warn, Error, Fatal, and Panic. (Default: Trace) NATS Message broker that drives Rhize&amp;rsquo;s event-based architecture.</description></item><item><title>GraphQL types and filters</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/reference/gql-types/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/reference/gql-types/</guid><description>This page provides a reference of the data types enforced by the Rhize database schema, and of the filters that can apply to these types when you query, update, or delete a set of resources. For an extended guide, with examples, read Use query filters.
Note These filters are based on Rhize&amp;rsquo;s implementation of the Dgraph @search directives. Data types Every object in the Rhize schema has fields that are of one of the basic data types.</description></item><item><title>Glossary</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/reference/glossary/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 19:35:35 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/reference/glossary/</guid><description>The manufacturing industry has many specialized terms—and many abbreviations. This glossary is a reference of how Rhize defines terms used in this documentation.
Agent The Rhize agent bridges your plant processes with the Rhize data hub. It collects data that is emitted during the manufacturing process and publishes it to the NATS message broker.Andon A system that alerts manufacturing teams about problems in processes or quality.Audit The Libre Audit log server is a service that provides a tamper-proof and immutable audit trail of all events that occur in the Rhize system.</description></item><item><title>Naming conventions</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/bpmn/naming-conventions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/bpmn/naming-conventions/</guid><description>Note These are recommendations. Your organization may adapt the conventions to its needs. Each BPMN workflow has an ID, as does each node in the workflow. Rhize recommends adopting a set of conventions about how you name these elements. Standardizing BPMN names across an environment has multiple benefits:
Consistent workflow naming conventions help you filter and find workflows in the process list. Well-named nodes make the workflow behavior easier to understand at a glance.</description></item><item><title>BMPN elements</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/bpmn/bpmn-elements/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 11:10:37 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/bpmn/bpmn-elements/</guid><description>This document describes the parameters available to each BPMN element in the Rhize UI. These parameters control how users set conditions, transform data, access variables, call services, and so on.
Rhize BPMN workflows conform to the visual grammar described in the OMG standard for Business Process Model and Notation. Each process is made of events (circles), activities (rectangles), gateways (diamonds), and flows (arrows). Some elements are extended for Rhize-specific features, such as service tasks that call the GraphQL API.</description></item></channel></rss>