<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Explanations on Rhize documentation</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/explanations/</link><description>Recent content in Explanations on Rhize documentation</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://docs.rhize.com/explanations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Manufacturing Data Hub</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/explanations/manufacturing-data-hub/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/explanations/manufacturing-data-hub/</guid><description>&lt;p>This article explains what the components of a &lt;em>Manufacturing Data Hub&lt;/em> (MDH) are and why the system must have these particular components to meet the needs of large, modern manufacturing environments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In another phrasing, this article explains why Rhize made the choices it did to become the world&amp;rsquo;s first manufacturing data hub.
For introductory explanations about Rhize in particular,
read &lt;a href="https://docs.rhize.com/get-started/introduction/">What is Rhize?&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://docs.rhize.com/get-started/how-rhize-works/">How Rhize works&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-an-mdh">What is an MDH?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A manufacturing data hub is a system that collects all manufacturing events, stores them in a standard model, and has a programmable engine that can run user logic to receive, transform, and send messages across different devices in a manufacturing operation.
As it comes with all the necessary backend components—message handling, logic, and storage—an MDH also serves as a backend for manufacturers to build custom MES and MOM applications.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ISA-95 diagrams</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/explanations/isa-95-diagrams/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/explanations/isa-95-diagrams/</guid><description>&lt;p>These diagrams provide some highly simplified visual explanations gleaned from parts of the thorough &lt;a href="https://www.isa.org/store?query=isa95">ISA-95 standard&lt;/a>.
To read about how the standard fits within the data architecture of Rhize, read our blog post &lt;a href="https://rhize.com/blog/reframing-perspective-on-isa95/">Rethinking perspectives on ISA-95&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="definition-demand-result">Definition, demand, result&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At a high-level, manufacturing consists of:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Goods being demanded&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Goods being produced&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Between these two points, the manufacturing operations performs this work according to its definitions
of work and the resources that it has available.
This diagram shows how ISA-95 defines these fundamental relationships from the perspective of the business (ERP) and manufacturing operation (MOM).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to speak ISA-95</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/explanations/how-to-speak-isa-95/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/explanations/how-to-speak-isa-95/</guid><description>&lt;p>ISA-95 provides a common language to discuss manufacturing.
When you speak with other manufacturing stakeholders, you can use the standard&amp;rsquo;s precise vocabulary to ensure that everyone is speaking about the same thing. The standard also describes how different manufacturing entities relate to each other.
You can use these relationships to create a full manufacturing data model.
Thus learning how to speak the language of ISA-95 can help standardize communication between both humans and machines.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>