<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Use GraphQL on Rhize documentation</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/gql/</link><description>Recent content in Use GraphQL on Rhize documentation</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 09:43:30 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/gql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Overview: the Rhize API</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/gql/call-the-graphql-api/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 09:43:30 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/gql/call-the-graphql-api/</guid><description>&lt;p>In a manufacturing operation, all event data is interrelated.
To make these relations explorable, Rhize stores data in a special-purpose graph database designed to represent all levels of the manufacturing process.
This database is enforced by our ISA-95 schema, the most comprehensive data representation of ISA-95 in the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rhize exposes this database through a &lt;a href="https://graphql.org/">GraphQL API&lt;/a>.
Unlike REST, GraphQL requires only one endpoint, and you can define exactly the data that you return for each operation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Query</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/gql/query/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/gql/query/</guid><description>&lt;p>A &lt;em>query&lt;/em> returns one or more resources from the database.
Whether you want to investigate manufacturing processes or build a custom report,
a good query is likely the foundation of your workflow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most queries start with these three verbs, each of which indicates the resources to return.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;code>get&lt;/code> for a single resource&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>query&lt;/code> for multiple resources&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>aggregate&lt;/code> for calculations on arrays&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>


&lt;div class="notices note" >
 &lt;span class="type">Note&lt;/span> These operations correspond to the &lt;code>Get&lt;/code> verb defined in &lt;a href="https://www.isa.org/products/ansi-isa-95-00-05-2018-enterprise-control-system-i">Part 5&lt;/a> of the ISA-95 standard.
&lt;/div>

&lt;h2 id="get">&lt;code>get&lt;/code> single resource&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Queries that start with &lt;code>get&lt;/code> return one object.
A common use of &lt;code>get&lt;/code> is to explore all data related to a particular object.
For example, in a custom dashboard, you may use &lt;code>getDataSource&lt;/code> to make a custom page that reports a specified data source.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Filter</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/gql/filter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/gql/filter/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Filters&lt;/em> limit an operation to a subset of resources.
You can use filters to make operations more precise, remove unneeded items from a payload, and reduce the need for secondary processing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To use a filter, specify it in the operation&amp;rsquo;s argument.
Most fields in an object can serve as a filter.


&lt;div class="notices note" >
 &lt;span class="type">Note&lt;/span> This page provides a detailed guide of how to use the filters, with examples.
For a bare reference of filters and data types, refer to the &lt;a href="https://docs.rhize.com/reference/gql-types/">GraphQL type reference&lt;/a>.
&lt;/div>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mutate</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/gql/mutate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/gql/mutate/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Mutations&lt;/em> change the database in someway by creating, updating, or deleting a resource.
You might use a mutation to update a personnel class, or in to a &lt;a href="https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/bpmn/">&lt;abbr title="Business Process Model and Notation. A standardized graphical notation used to represent business processes in an intuitive, visual way. Rhize&amp;#39;s BPMN UI and engine provides a low-code interface for complex event handling">BPMN&lt;/abbr>&lt;/a> workflow that automatically creates records of incoming material lots.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rhize supports the following ways to change the API.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Subscribe</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/gql/subscribe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/gql/subscribe/</guid><description>&lt;p>The operations for a &lt;code>subscription&lt;/code> are similar to the operations for a &lt;a href="https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/gql/query/">&lt;code>query&lt;/code>&lt;/a>.
But rather than providing information about the entire item, the purpose of subscriptions is to notify about real-time changes to a manufacturing resource.&lt;/p>


&lt;div class="notices note" >
 &lt;span class="type">Note&lt;/span> These operations correspond to the &lt;code>SyncGet&lt;/code> verb defined in &lt;a href="https://www.isa.org/products/ansi-isa-95-00-05-2018-enterprise-control-system-i">Part 5&lt;/a> of the ISA-95 standard.
&lt;/div>

&lt;p>This example query subscribes to changes in a specified set of &lt;code>workResponses&lt;/code>, reporting only their &lt;code>id&lt;/code> and effective end time.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>