<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Maintain on Rhize documentation</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/maintain/</link><description>Recent content in Maintain on Rhize documentation</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 11:20:56 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/maintain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Archive the PostgreSQL Audit trail</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/maintain/audit/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 11:20:56 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/maintain/audit/</guid><description>The audit trial can generate a high volume of data, so it is a good practice to periodically archive portions of it. An archive separates a portion of the data from the database and keeps it for long-term storage. This process involves the use of PostgreSQL Table Partitions.
Archiving a partition improves query speed for current data, while providing a cost-effective way to store older.
Prerequisites Before you start, ensure you have the following:</description></item><item><title>BPMN execution recovery</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/maintain/bpmn-nodes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/maintain/bpmn-nodes/</guid><description>BPMN processes often have longer execution durations and many steps. If a BPMN node suddenly fails (for example through a panic or loss of power), Rhize needs to ensure that the workflow completes.
To achieve high availability and resiliency, Rhize services run in Kubernetes nodes, and the NATS message broker typically has data replication. As long as the remaining BPMN nodes are not already at full processing capacity, if a BPMN node fails while executing a process, the Rhize system recovers and finishes the workflow.</description></item></channel></rss>