<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>how-to on</title><link>https://libremfg.github.io/categories/how-to/</link><description>Recent content in how-to on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 14:49:53 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://libremfg.github.io/categories/how-to/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Overview</title><link>https://libremfg.github.io/deploy/install/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://libremfg.github.io/deploy/install/overview/</guid><description>This guide walks you through how to Install Rhize and its services in a Kubernetes environment. You can also use these docs to model automation workflows in your CI.
This procedure aims to be as generic and vendor-neutral as possible. Some configuration depends on where and how you run your IT infrastructure—what cloud provider you use, preferred auxiliary tools, and so on&amp;mdash;so your team must adapt the process for its particular use cases.</description></item><item><title>Set up Kubernetes</title><link>https://libremfg.github.io/deploy/install/setup-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 14:49:53 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://libremfg.github.io/deploy/install/setup-kubernetes/</guid><description>This guide shows you how to install Rhize services on your Kubernetes cluster. You can also use this procedure as the model for an automation workflow in your CI.
Prerequisites Before starting, ensure that you have the following technical requirements.
Software requirements:
kubectl Helm Curl, or some similar program to make HTTP requests from the command line Access requirements:
Administrative privileges for a running Kubernetes cluster in your environment. Your organization must set this up.</description></item><item><title>Configure Keycloak</title><link>https://libremfg.github.io/deploy/install/keycloak/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://libremfg.github.io/deploy/install/keycloak/</guid><description>Rhize uses Keycloak as an OpenID provider. In your cluster, the Keycloak server to authenticate users, services, and manage Role-based access controls.
This topic describes how to set up Keycloak in your Rhize cluster. For a conceptual overview of the authentication flow, read About OpenID Connect
Prerequisites First, ensure that you have followed the instructions from Set up Kubernetes. All prerequisites for that step apply here.
Log in Go to localhost on the port where you forwarded the URL.</description></item><item><title>Install Rhize services</title><link>https://libremfg.github.io/deploy/install/services/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://libremfg.github.io/deploy/install/services/</guid><description>The final installation step is to install the Rhize services in your Kubernetes cluster.
Prerequisites This topic assumes you have Set up Kubernetes and Configured Keycloak. All the prerequisites for those topics apply here. Configure load balancing for the following DNS records: Service Domain Admin UI &amp;lt;CUSTOMER&amp;gt;-libre.libremfg.ai Keycloak &amp;lt;CUSTOMER&amp;gt;-auth.libremfg.ai GraphQL &amp;lt;CUSTOMER&amp;gt;-graphql.libremfg.ai NATS &amp;lt;CUSTOMER&amp;gt;-mqtt.libremfg.ai Highbyte &amp;lt;CUSTOMER&amp;gt;-highbyte.libremfg.ai Grafana &amp;lt;CUSTOMER&amp;gt;-grafana.libremfg.ai BPMN &amp;lt;CUSTOMER&amp;gt;-bpmn.libremfg.ai Overrides Each service is installed through a Helm YAML file. For some of these services, you might need to edit this file to add credential information and modify defaults.</description></item></channel></rss>