<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>reference on</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/categories/reference/</link><description>Recent content in reference on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 16:29:21 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.rhize.com/categories/reference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Master definitions and fields</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/model/master-definitions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 16:29:21 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/model/master-definitions/</guid><description>To make a production object visible to the Rhize data hub, you must define it as a data model.
These sections document all the objects that you can add through the UI, and the fields and properties that you can associate with them. All these models are based on the ISA-95 standard, mostly from Part 2, which describes the role-based equipment hierarchy.
Global object fields All objects that you define must have a unique name.</description></item><item><title>BMPN elements</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/bpmn/bpmn-elements/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 11:10:37 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/bpmn/bpmn-elements/</guid><description>These pages describe the elements to make a Rhize BPMN workflow, and their parameters to set conditions, use variables, and call services.
Rhize BPMN elements are based on the Business Process Model and Notation OMG Standard. While the visual grammar is functionally the same, we extend some elements for specific Rhize features, like service tasks that call the GraphQL API.
Each BPMN workflow is a process with an ID. Each process is made up events (circles), activities (rectangles), gateways (diamonds), and flows (arrows).</description></item><item><title>Default local ports</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/reference/default-ports/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 16:49:42 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/reference/default-ports/</guid><description>After you install Rhize services, they are accessible, by default, on the following ports:
Service Default Port Admin UI localhost:3030 Grafana localhost:3001 Router localhost:4000 Keycloak localhost:8090 baas-alpha command line localhost:8080</description></item><item><title>Agent configuration</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/reference/agent-configuration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/reference/agent-configuration/</guid><description>The Rhize agent collects data that is emitted in the manufacturing process and makes this data visible in the Rhize system. It works by connecting to equipment or groups of equipment that run over protocols such as OPC UA.
As the communication bridge between the Rhize Data Hub and your plant, the agent has multiple functions:
It subscribes to tags and republishes the changes in NATS. It creates an interface for the BPMN engine to send reads and writes to a data source and its associated equipment.</description></item><item><title>Glossary</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/reference/glossary/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 19:35:35 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/reference/glossary/</guid><description>The manufacturing industry has many specialized terms—and many abbreviations. This glossary is a reference of how Rhize defines terms used in this documentation.
Agent The Rhize agent bridges your plant processes with the Rhize data hub. It collects data that is emitted during the manufacturing process and publishes it to the NATS message broker. Andon A system that alerts manufacturing teams about problems in processes or quality. Audit The Libre Audit log server is a service that provides a tamper-proof and immutable audit trail of all events that occur in the Rhize system.</description></item></channel></rss>