<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Releases on Rhize documentation</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/categories/releases/</link><description>Recent content in Releases on Rhize documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 11:09:55 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.rhize.com/categories/releases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Rhize 3.0</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/releases/3-0/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 09:17:43 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/releases/3-0/</guid><description>Rhize version 3.0 is now in general release! &amp;#x1f973; As a full rewrite of our earlier Libre 2.0 application, this release functionally announces a new product.
Read more to learn about the features available in the Rhize Manufacturing Data Hub.
What is Rhize? Rhize is the world&amp;rsquo;s first manufacturing data hub. It collects event data emitted from all levels of a manufacturing process, stores this data in a standardized schema, and exposes access to the event stream so users can orchestrate workflows in real-time.</description></item><item><title>3.0.0 (general release)</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/releases/changelog/3-0-0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 11:09:55 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/releases/changelog/3-0-0/</guid><description>Changelog for version 3.0.0 of the Rhize application.
Release date: 25th March, 2024
Breaking changes Changes by service Admin UI Features
Add includesPropertiesOf input when creating a new version of OperationsEventClass Add IncludesPropertiesOf option to Equipment Class General tab Add momentjs for timezones as select in Equipment Version timezone field Add BPMN side panel for OPCUA Method Call Add clear option to WorkMaster disable modal Add edits for Static properties Add enable and disable functionality to work calendar definition Add EquipmentClass ISA-95 property type selection Add EquipmentLevel to Equipment Class Add inheritance of Operational Location Class properties into Operational Location Add inherited properties from linked Operations Event Class to Operations Event Class properties page Add manufacturer to Physical Asset Class general tab Add new modal to BPMN Add new Work Calendar Definition select on Equipment Version management Add Operational Location and Spatial Definition to Equipment General tab Add OperationsEventClass to OperationsEventDefinition Add option to disable Operations Definition Add option to disable previous work master version when create a new version Add option to disable Work Calendar Definition Property Add option to disable Work Calendar Entry Add option to enable a disabled Process Segment Add page to add manual Work Calendar Entries Add pagination to Work Calendar Entries Add properties to Work Calendar Definition Add Published date and Hierarchy Scope to WorkMaster Add relationship between Operations Event Definition and Work Master Add scrollbar to Work Calendar Definition Add Spatial Definition to Physical Location &amp;amp; Physical Asset Add start weekday selection to Work Calendar Definition Add static properties on Equipment Class Add timezone on Work Calendar Add timezone on Work Calendar Entry and Equipment Add user store to UserManager and set automatic silent renew Add Work Calendar Definition manage entries component Add Work Calendar Definition management Add Work Calendar Setup Change</description></item><item><title>3.0.0rc09</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/releases/changelog/3-0-0rc09/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 11:09:55 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/releases/changelog/3-0-0rc09/</guid><description>Changelog for version 3.0.0rc9 of the Rhize application.
Release date: 27th February, 2024
Breaking changes Changes by service Admin UI No changes since previous release.
Agent Features
Add check to validate OPC UA topics against server metadata Add hostname in message payload Add logic for MQTT connections to resubscribe on disconnect Add option to deconstruct complex JSON payloads to simple types Audit Features
Add previous audit value relative to current BAAS Changes</description></item><item><title>3.0.0rc08</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/releases/changelog/3-0-0rc08/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 13:01:02 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/releases/changelog/3-0-0rc08/</guid><description>Changelog for version 3.0.0rc08 of the Rhize application.
Release date: 19th December, 2023
Breaking changes [ADMINUI] Change UI navigation bar design [SCHEMA] Change OperationsEventClass.IncludedIn to reference an OperationsEventClassVersion instead of OperationsEventClass [SCHEMA] Change OperationsEventClass.IncludesPropertiesOf to move to the version instance, OperationsEventClassVersion.IncludesPropertiesOf, instead of header [SCHEMA] Change OperationsEventDefinition.IncludedIn to reference an OperationsEventDefinitionVersion instead of OperationsEventDefinition [SCHEMA] Change OperationsEventDefinition.IncludesPropertiesOf to move to the version instance, OperationsEventDefinitionVersion.IncludesPropertiesOf, instead of header [SCHEMA] Change FromResourceReference and ToResourceReference to combine them into a single resourceReference Changes by service Admin UI Features</description></item><item><title>3.0.0rc07</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/releases/changelog/3-0-0rc07/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 09:32:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/releases/changelog/3-0-0rc07/</guid><description>Changelog for version 3.0.0rc07 of the Rhize application.
Release date: 15th November, 2023
Breaking changes [SCHEMA] Change types OperationalLocationClass, OperationalLocationClassVersion, OperationalLocationClassProperty, OperationalLocation, OperationalLocationVersion and OperationalLocationProperty to have: isPartOf (0..1), isMadeUpOf (0..*) [BPMN] Change CommandConsumer and Timers to use new JetStream library and durable consumers. This requires you to drop and re-create streams KV_JobResponses, KV_WorkflowSpecifications, libreBpmn_Command and libreTimerStart. Changes by service Admin UI Features
Add ability to create Process Segment Version Add ability to edit linked process segment resource specification property Add ability to link a Hierarchy Scope to a Operational Location Class version Add check for renaming a linked property with an existing property name Add Homepage screen Add optional link from Operational Location Class to a Operational Location Class version Add Physical Asset Properties Add Physical Asset Resource Specifications Change</description></item><item><title>3.0.0rc06</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/releases/changelog/3-0-0rc06/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 21:07:43 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/releases/changelog/3-0-0rc06/</guid><description>Changelog for version 3.0.0rc06 of the Rhize application.
Release date: October 31, 2023
Breaking changes NATS streams libreBpmn_command and LibreTimerStart must be deleted prior to starting Changes by service Core Features
Add mutation for dependency check for DataSource, Equipment, EquipmentClass, OperationalLocation, and OperationalLocationClass Changes
Change to go-module for schema Change struct literal unkeyed fields to keyed BPMN Breaking Changes
NATS streams libreBpmn_command and LibreTimerStart must be deleted prior to starting Features</description></item><item><title>3.0.0rc05</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/releases/changelog/3-0-0rc05/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 20:32:34 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/releases/changelog/3-0-0rc05/</guid><description>Changelog for version 3.0.0rc05 of the Rhize application.
Release date: October 24, 2023
Breaking changes Renamed UI environment variables and changed KEYCLOACK to KEYCLOAK Changes by service Core Features
Add deleteSyncEquipmentsFromDBtoNATSStatus mutation Add NATS connection name Add fields to InformationObject Fixes
Fix tracing typo Changes
Change Core to purge keys that are not in the the database Change core to delete property value from KV when the equipment no longer have active version BPMN Features</description></item></channel></rss>