<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Use work calendars on Rhize documentation</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/work-calendars/</link><description>Recent content in Use work calendars on Rhize documentation</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/work-calendars/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About calendars and overrides</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/work-calendars/about-calendars-and-overrides/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/work-calendars/about-calendars-and-overrides/</guid><description>Work calendars represent planned periods of time in your operation, including shifts, planned shutdowns, or recurring stops for maintenance. The Rhize API represents calendars through a workCalendar entity and this calendar&amp;rsquo;s associated definitions and entries. They provide helpful abstractions for activities such as scheduling and performance analysis.
Rhize has an optional calendar service that periodically queries the Rhize DB for workCalendarDefinitions. If it finds active definitions and equipment for that period, the service creates work calendar entries and persists the data to a time-series database.</description></item><item><title>Create work calendars</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/work-calendars/create-work-calendar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/work-calendars/create-work-calendar/</guid><description>This guide shows you how to create a work calendar using the Rhize GraphQL API. As a calendar has associations with multiple other entities, the process involves a series of mutations to create associated data.
To learn how work calendars work, read About work calendars.
Prerequisites To use the work calendar service, ensure you have the following:
The calendar service installed A plan for how to organize and name your calendars according to equipment.</description></item></channel></rss>