<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>BMPN elements on </title>
    <link>https://MattDodsonEnglish.github.io/libremfg.github.io/pull/20/reference/bpmn/</link>
    <description>Recent content in BMPN elements on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 11:10:37 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://MattDodsonEnglish.github.io/libremfg.github.io/pull/20/reference/bpmn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Events</title>
      <link>https://MattDodsonEnglish.github.io/libremfg.github.io/pull/20/reference/bpmn/events/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 11:10:37 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://MattDodsonEnglish.github.io/libremfg.github.io/pull/20/reference/bpmn/events/</guid>
      <description>Events are something that happen in the course of a process. In BPMN, events are drawn with circles.
In event-driven models, events can happen in one of three dimensions:
Start. All processes begin with some trigger that starts an event. Start events are drawn with a single thin circle.
Intermediate. Possible events between the start and end. Intermediate events might start from some trigger, or create some result. They are drawn with a double thin line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activities</title>
      <link>https://MattDodsonEnglish.github.io/libremfg.github.io/pull/20/reference/bpmn/activities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 11:10:37 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://MattDodsonEnglish.github.io/libremfg.github.io/pull/20/reference/bpmn/activities/</guid>
      <description>In BPMN, an activity is work performed within a business process.
On the Rhize platform, most activities are tasks, work that cannot be broken down into smaller levels of detail. Tasks are drawn with rectangles with rounded corners. Besides tasks, you can also use call activities, processes which call and invoke other processes.
As with Gateways and events, service and call activities types are marked by their icons.
Service task templates Service tasks have a gear icon marker</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gateways</title>
      <link>https://MattDodsonEnglish.github.io/libremfg.github.io/pull/20/reference/bpmn/gateways/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 11:10:37 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://MattDodsonEnglish.github.io/libremfg.github.io/pull/20/reference/bpmn/gateways/</guid>
      <description>Gateways control how sequence flows interact as they converge and diverge within a process. They represent mechanisms that either allow or disallow a passage.
BPMN notation represents gateways as diamonds with single thin lines, as is common in many diagrams with decision flows. Besides decisions, however, Rhize&amp;rsquo;s BPMN notation also includes parellel gateways.
As with Events and Activities, gateway types are marked by their icons.
Drawn as diamonds, gateways represent branches in a sequence flow.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
