<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Use-Cases on Rhize documentation</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/categories/use-cases/</link><description>Recent content in Use-Cases on Rhize documentation</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://docs.rhize.com/categories/use-cases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data collection (eBR example)</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/use-cases/data-collection-ebr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/use-cases/data-collection-ebr/</guid><description>&lt;div class="notices note" >
 &lt;span class="type">Note&lt;/span> Looking to implement Rhize for your Pharma operation?
&lt;a href="https://rhize.com/contact-us/">Talk to an engineer&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>This document provides examples of how you can use Rhize to automatically ingest data from various sources and store it in a standardized ISA-95 schema.
The examples here are to produce an Electronic Batch Record, an important use case in pharmaceutical manufacturing.
However, the process described here is very similar to what data collection would like when integrating with any third-party system (such as an MRP, CMMS, and so on), no matter the type of manufacturing process.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Electronic Batch Records</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/use-cases/ebr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/use-cases/ebr/</guid><description>&lt;p>This document shows you how to use ISA-95 and Rhize to create a generic, reusable model for any use case that involves &lt;em>Electronic batch records&lt;/em>.
As long as you properly &lt;a href="https://docs.rhize.com/use-cases/data-collection-ebr/">map and ingest&lt;/a> the source data,
the provided queries here should work for any operation, though you&amp;rsquo;ll need to tweak them to fit the particular structure of your job response and reporting requirements.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An Electronic Batch Record (eBR) is a detailed report about a specific batch.
Generating eBRs is an important component of pharmaceutical manufacturing, whose high standards of compliance and complexity of inputs demand a great deal of detail in each report.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Genealogy</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/use-cases/genealogy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/use-cases/genealogy/</guid><description>&lt;p>This document provides a high-level overview of how to use Rhize for material genealogy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In manufacturing, a &lt;em>genealogy&lt;/em> is the record of what a material contains or what it is now a part of.
As its name implies, genealogy represents the family tree of the material.
A material genealogy can help manufacturers in multiple ways:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Prevent product recalls by isolating deviations early in the material flow&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Decrease recall time by having a complete record of where material starts and ends&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Help build reports and analysis of material deviations&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create documentation and compliance records for material tracking&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Rhize provides a standards-based schema to represent material at all levels of granularity.
The graph structure of its DB has built-in properties to associate material lots with other information about planned and performed work.
This database has a GraphQL API, which can pull full genealogies from terse queries.
As such, Rhize makes an &lt;strong>ideal backend to use for genealogical use cases&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>