<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Define production models on Rhize documentation</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/model/</link><description>Recent content in Define production models on Rhize documentation</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 15:36:03 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/model/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create objects from the UI</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/model/create-objects-ui/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 15:36:03 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/model/create-objects-ui/</guid><description>To make a production object visible to the Rhize data hub, you must define it as a data model. Along with its API, Rhize also has a graphical interface to create and update objects in your role-based equipment hierarchy.
Often, one object references another: for example, a piece of equipment may belong to an equipment class, have a unit of measure as a property, and be associated with process segment. These associations form nodes and edges in your knowledge graph, so the more information relationships that you accurately create, the better.</description></item><item><title>Master definitions and fields</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/model/master-definitions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 16:29:21 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/model/master-definitions/</guid><description>To make a production object visible to the Rhize data hub, you must define it as a data model.
These sections document all the objects that you can add through the UI, and the fields and properties that you can associate with them. All these models are based on the ISA-95 standard, mostly from Part 2, which describes the role-based equipment hierarchy.
Note For visual examples of how some of these models relate, look at our page of ISA-95 Diagrams.</description></item></channel></rss>