<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ratel UI on</title><link>/ratel/</link><description>Recent content in Ratel UI on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/ratel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Backups</title><link>/ratel/backups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ratel/backups/</guid><description>Backup Here you will find options to backup your server.
Note This backup option is an Enterprise feature. Creating a Backup Click on Create Backup. On the dialog box, you will choose the destination details. After the successful backup it will be listed on the main panel.</description></item><item><title>Cluster</title><link>/ratel/cluster/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ratel/cluster/</guid><description>Cluster Management Here you will find the basic information about the cluster.
The Zero list with license and the list of zeros connected:
Each card represents a zero node. The card has a green sign which shows the health. It shows the address of the node and a little blue banner indicating that this node is the leader. The Alpha list separated into groups:
You have a list of tablets that exist on that group and their approximate size.</description></item><item><title>Connection</title><link>/ratel/connection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ratel/connection/</guid><description>Recent Servers This section provides a list of recent connected clusters. You can select any item on the list to connect.
The list also has an icon which indicates the version of the cluster running:
Green icon: Running the latest version. Yellow icon: Running a specific version. Red icon: No connection found. Delete icon: Remove the address form the list. URL Input box In this box you add a valid Dgraph Alpha address.</description></item><item><title>Console</title><link>/ratel/console/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ratel/console/</guid><description>Query Panel You can execute two kinds of operations: Queries and Mutations. The history section holds either queries or mutations.
Query On this panel, you can only run DQL (former GraphQL+-). You can use # to comment on something. You also have the DQL Variable; see more at DQL.
Mutation On this panel, you can run RDF and JSON mutations.
Result Panel Graph On this tab you can view the query results in a Graph format.</description></item><item><title>Ratel Overview</title><link>/ratel/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ratel/overview/</guid><description>Ratel is a tool for data visualization and cluster management that&amp;rsquo;s designed from the ground-up to work with Dgraph and DQL. You can use it for the following types of tasks:
Connect to a backend and manage cluster settings (see Connection) Run DQL queries and mutations, and see results (see Console) Update or replace your DQL schema, and drop data (see Schema) Get information on cluster nodes and remove nodes (see Cluster) Backup your server if you are using self-managed Dgraph (see Backup) To get started with Ratel, use it online with the Dgraph Ratel Dashboard or clone and build Ratel using the instructions from the Ratel repository on GitHub.</description></item><item><title>Schema</title><link>/ratel/schema/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ratel/schema/</guid><description>Predicate Section You have two panels:
The left panel with a predicate list in a table. The table consists of three columns, the name of the predicate, the type, and the indices. On the right panel you have the properties related to the selection from the right panel. You can add new predicates using the Add Predicate button on the top left corner. In the dialog box, you can add the name of the predicate, the type, language if required, and its indices.</description></item></channel></rss>