<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>concepts on</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/categories/concepts/</link><description>Recent content in concepts on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 19:39:39 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.rhize.com/categories/concepts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What is Rhize?</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/get-started/introduction/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 12:25:46 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/get-started/introduction/</guid><description>Rhize is a real-time, event-driven manufacturing data hub. It unites data analysis, event monitoring, and process execution in one platform. Its interface and architecture is designed to conform to your processes. We assume nothing about what your manufacturing workflows look like.
Rhize has only one strong opinion: all manufacturing objects and data must be modeled on the ISA-95 standard. This standards-based schema is how Rhize connects every data event across an entire operation.</description></item><item><title>How Rhize works</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/get-started/how-rhize-works/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 19:39:39 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/get-started/how-rhize-works/</guid><description>This article provides a high-level overview of how Rhize works, starting with data collection and ending with user interaction. To make these concepts more concrete, the next section provides examples of each process.
The heart of the Rhize platform is its manufacturing knowledge graph, which stores data from all levels of the operation and exposes this data through a single endpoint. Around the database are services that exchange messages and process events in real-time.</description></item><item><title>Concepts</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/concepts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/concepts/</guid><description>The design of the Rhize Manufacturing Data Hub comes from decades of work in industrial automation. Time and again, we discovered data infrastructure and level-3 systems with the same problems:
They don&amp;rsquo;t scale across organizations They don&amp;rsquo;t integrate with existing systems They fundamentally don&amp;rsquo;t respect the complexity of the manufacturing problem space. This experience led us to build the system that we always wished existed: the Manufacturing Data Hub. These topics explain the concepts, architecture, and design philosophy that underpin the design of Rhize.</description></item><item><title>BPMN execution recovery</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/restore/bpmn-nodes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/restore/bpmn-nodes/</guid><description>BPMN processes often have longer execution durations and many steps. If a BPMN node suddenly fails (for example through a panic or loss of power), Rhize needs to ensure that the workflow completes.
To achieve high availability and resiliency, Rhize services run in Kubernetes nodes, and the NATS message broker typically has data replication. As long as the remaining BPMN nodes are not already at full processing capacity, if a BPMN node fails while executing a process, the Rhize system recovers and finishes the workflow.</description></item><item><title>About OpenID connect</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/about-openidconnect/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/about-openidconnect/</guid><description>Rhize uses OpenIDConnect to connect to a Keycloak server to authenticate users and manage Role-based access controls.
Open ID Connect is a security architecture that uses JSON Web Tokens (JWTs) to access secured resources. JWTs are issued by Keycloak. Users can also be managed in Keycloak. Or you can manage users in other services such as LDAP, Google, Azure AD, Facebook, etc.
The general authentication flow is as follows:
When a user accesses the user interface, the UI redirects to Keycloak.</description></item></channel></rss>