<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>How-To on</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/categories/how-to/</link><description>Recent content in How-To on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 19:10:43 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.rhize.com/categories/how-to/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create objects from the UI</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/model/create-objects-ui/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 15:36:03 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/model/create-objects-ui/</guid><description>To make a production object visible to the Rhize data hub, you must define it as a data model. Along with its API, Rhize also has a graphical interface to create and update objects in your role-based equipment hierarchy.
Often, one object references another: for example, a piece of equipment may belong to an equipment class, have a unit of measure as a property, and be associated with process segment. These associations form nodes and edges in your knowledge graph, so the more information relationships that you accurately create, the better.</description></item><item><title>Overview</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/install/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/install/overview/</guid><description>This guide walks you through how to Install Rhize and its services in a Kubernetes environment. You can also use these docs to model automation workflows in your CI.
This procedure aims to be as generic and vendor-neutral as possible. Some configuration depends on where and how you run your IT infrastructure—what cloud provider you use, preferred auxiliary tools, and so on&amp;mdash;so your team must adapt the process for its particular use cases.</description></item><item><title>Connect data source</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/publish-subscribe/connect-datasource/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 14:50:39 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/publish-subscribe/connect-datasource/</guid><description>For Rhize to listen to and handle manufacturing events, you need to connect a data source.
Prerequisites To add a data source, you need the following:
Access to an MQTT or OPC UA server Credentials for this server, if necessary The URL and connection string for this server (Rhize will point to this) Steps to connect The process has two sides:
Sending topics from your MQTT, OPCUA, or NATS server to Rhize.</description></item><item><title>Set up Kubernetes</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/install/setup-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 14:49:53 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/install/setup-kubernetes/</guid><description>This guide shows you how to install Rhize services on your Kubernetes cluster. You can also use this procedure as the model for an automation workflow in your CI.
Prerequisites Before starting, ensure that you have the following technical requirements.
Software requirements:
kubectl Helm Curl, or some similar program to make HTTP requests from the command line Access requirements:
Administrative privileges for a running Kubernetes cluster in your environment. Your organization must set this up.</description></item><item><title>Overview: the Rhize API</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/gql/call-the-graphql-api/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 09:43:30 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/gql/call-the-graphql-api/</guid><description>In a manufacturing operation, all event data is interrelated. To make these relations explorable, Rhize stores data in a special-purpose graph database designed to represent all levels of the manufacturing process. This database is enforced by our ISA-95 schema, the most comprehensive data representation of ISA-95 in the world.
Rhize exposes this database through a GraphQL API. Unlike REST, GraphQL requires only one endpoint, and you can define exactly the data that you return for each operation.</description></item><item><title>Back up the Graph DB</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/backup/graphdb/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 11:01:46 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/backup/graphdb/</guid><description>This guide shows you how to back up the Rhize Graph database. You can also use it to model an automation workflow.
Prerequisites Before you start, ensure you have the following:
A designated backup location, for example ~/rhize-backups/database. Access to your Rhize Kubernetes Environment Optional: kubectx utilities kubectx to manage multiple clusters kubens to switch between and configure namespaces easily Optional: the k8 Lens IDE, if you prefer to use Kubernetes graphically.</description></item><item><title>Define production models</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/model/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 14:50:39 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/model/</guid><description>You have multiple ways to update your production models:
Use the UI to define it for an individual unit or class POST a batch over the GraphQL API Use BPMN as a filter receive an incoming ERP document and map into the system The trade offs are usually upfront configuration time, number of items to add, and level of automation. Adding an item over the UI requires no programming skill, but you can only add only one unit at a time.</description></item><item><title>Configure Keycloak</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/install/keycloak/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/install/keycloak/</guid><description>Rhize uses Keycloak as an OpenID provider. In your cluster, the Keycloak server to authenticate users, services, and manage Role-based access controls.
This topic describes how to set up Keycloak in your Rhize cluster. For a conceptual overview of the authentication flow, read About OpenID Connect
Prerequisites First, ensure that you have followed the instructions from Set up Kubernetes. All prerequisites for that step apply here.
Steps Follow these steps to configure a Keycloak realm and associate Rhize services to Keycloak clients, groups, roles, and policies.</description></item><item><title>Install Rhize services</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/install/services/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/install/services/</guid><description>The final installation step is to install the Rhize services in your Kubernetes cluster.
Prerequisites This topic assumes you have done the following:
Set up Kubernetes and Configured Keycloak. All the prerequisites for those topics apply here.
Configured load balancing for the following DNS records:
Where PREFIX is a name to identify the application&amp;mdash;preferably Rhize&amp;mdash; and YOUR_DOMAIN is the domain you run Rhize on. For example: rhize-ui.example.com. Service Domain Admin UI &amp;lt;PREFIX&amp;gt;-ui.</description></item><item><title>Connect event data</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/publish-subscribe/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 14:50:39 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/publish-subscribe/</guid><description>For Rhize to listen to and handle manufacturing events, you need to connect a data source.</description></item><item><title>Turn values into events</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/publish-subscribe/turn-value-into-event/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 19:10:43 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/publish-subscribe/turn-value-into-event/</guid><description>A data source can emit a high volume of data, but not all this data is useful. To filter for significant events, use the rules engine to write rules to that trigger workflows when conditions are met.
The rules engine evaluates incoming values from a data source and converts significant changes into events to be processed by a BPMN workflow. Each rule exists on the level of the equipment class. Each rule evaluates changes that happen to a set of specified properties for a data source.</description></item><item><title>Back up</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/backup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 19:35:35 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/backup/</guid><description>Backup is critical to ensure reliability and recovery.
These guides show you how to back up different services and data on Rhize. They also serve as blueprints for automation.
Your organization must determine how frequently you backup services, and how long you store them for. The correct practice here is highly contextual, depending on the size of the data, the importance of the data, and the general regulatory and governance demands of your industry.</description></item><item><title>Restore</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/restore/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 19:35:35 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/restore/</guid><description>These guides show you how to restore data from backup. They also serve as blueprints for automation.
Even if you don&amp;rsquo;t need to restore data, it&amp;rsquo;s a good practice to test restoration periodically.</description></item><item><title>Query</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/gql/query/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/gql/query/</guid><description>A query returns one or more resources from the database. Whether you want to investigate manufacturing processes or build a custom report, a good query is likely the foundation of your workflow.
Most queries start with these three verbs, each of which indicates the resources to return.
get for a single resource query for multiple resources aggregate for calculations on arrays Note These operations correspond to the Get verb defined in Part 5 of the ISA-95 standard.</description></item><item><title>Filter</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/gql/filter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/gql/filter/</guid><description>Filters limit an operation to a subset of resources. You can use filters to make operations more precise, remove unneeded items from a payload, and reduce the need for secondary processing.
To use a filter, specify it in the operation&amp;rsquo;s argument. Most fields in an object can serve as a filter. Note This page provides a detailed guide of how to use the filters, with examples. For a bare reference of filters and data types, refer to the GraphQL type reference.</description></item><item><title>Mutate</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/gql/mutate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/gql/mutate/</guid><description>Mutations change the database in someway by creating, updating, or deleting a resource. You might use a mutation to update a personnel class, or in to a BPMN workflow that automatically creates records of incoming material lots.
Rhize supports the following ways to change the API.
add Note The add operation corresponds to the Process verb defined in Part 5 of the ISA-95 standard. Mutations that start with add create a resource on the server.</description></item><item><title>Subscribe</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/gql/subscribe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/gql/subscribe/</guid><description>The operations for a subscription are similar to the operations for a query. But rather than providing information about the entire item, the purpose of subscriptions is to notify about real-time changes to a manufacturing resource.
Note These operations correspond to the SyncGet verb defined in Part 5 of the ISA-95 standard. This example query subscribes to changes in a specified set of workResponses, reporting only their id and effective end time.</description></item><item><title>Tune BPMN performance</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/bpmn/tune-performance/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 09:47:47 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/bpmn/tune-performance/</guid><description>This page documents some tips to debug BPMN workflows and improve their performance.
Manufacturing events can generate a vast amount of data. And a BPMN workflow can have any number of logical flows and data transformations. So an inefficient BPMN process can introduce performance degradations.
Manage the process context size Note The max size of the process variable context comes from the default max payload size of NATS Jetstreams. To increase this size, change your NATS configuration.</description></item><item><title>Back up Keycloak</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/backup/keycloak/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 14:30:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/backup/keycloak/</guid><description>This guide shows you how to back up Keycloak on your Rhize Kubernetes deployment.
Prerequisites Before you start, ensure you have the following:
A designated backup location, for example ~/rhize-backups/keycloak. Access to the Rhize Kubernetes Environment Optional: kubectx utilities kubectx to manage multiple clusters kubens to switch between and configure namespaces easily Optional: the k8 Lens IDE, if you prefer to use Kubernetes graphically Also, before you start, confirm you are in the right context and namespace.</description></item><item><title>Restore Keycloak</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/restore/keycloak/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 13:26:23 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/restore/keycloak/</guid><description>This guide shows you how to restore Keycloak in your Rhize environment.
Caution Restoring Keycloak to a running instance involves downtime.
Typically, this downtime lasts less than a minute. The exact duration needed depends on network constraints, backup size, and the performance of the Kubernetes cluster.
Prerequisites Before you start, ensure you have the following:
kubectl A Keycloak backup Steps Confirm the cluster and namespace are correct:
## context kubectl config current-context ## namespace kubectl get namespace To change the namespace for all subsequent kubectl commands to libre, run this command:</description></item><item><title>Restore Grafana</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/restore/grafana/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 13:52:23 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/restore/grafana/</guid><description>This guide shows you how to restore Grafana in your Rhize environment.
Prerequisites Before you start, ensure you have the following:
kubectl A Grafana backup Steps Confirm the cluster and namespace are correct:
## context kubectl config current-context ## namespace kubectl get namespace To change the namespace for all subsequent kubectl commands to libre, run this command:
kubectl config set-context --current --namespace=libre For a reference of useful kubectl commands, refer to the official kubectl Cheat Sheet.</description></item><item><title>Back up Grafana</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/backup/grafana/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 11:01:56 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/backup/grafana/</guid><description>This guide shows you the procedure to back up Grafana on your Rhize Kubernetes deployment. For general instructions, refer to the official Back up Grafana documentation.
Prerequisites Before you start, ensure you have the following:
A designated backup location, for example ~/rhize-backups/grafana. Access to the Rhize Kubernetes Environment Optional: kubectx utilities kubectx to manage multiple clusters kubens to switch between and configure namespaces easily Optional: the k8 Lens IDE, if you prefer to use Kubernetes graphically Also, before you start, confirm you are in the right context and namespace.</description></item><item><title>Create workflows</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/bpmn/create-workflow/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 14:50:39 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/bpmn/create-workflow/</guid><description>This topic shows you how to use the BPMN UI to create event-driven workflows. To view the full list of elements and their parameters, refer to BPMN elements.
Prerequisites To create a workflow, you&amp;rsquo;ll need:
An installed environment Topics to publish and subscribe to The ability to call the GraphQL API and understand JSON. General procedures Every workflow is different, but the overall procedure usually works like this:
Create a start event:</description></item><item><title>Write BPMN workflows</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/bpmn/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 14:50:39 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/bpmn/</guid><description>The heart of a manufacturing process is not data, but the event.
For its event handling, Rhize uses a custom BPMN engine:
The low-code, graphical notation makes workflow programming accessible to more people in your operation Its event-based workflows can listen for events published to the message broker, and send messages back The service task interface can make GraphQL queries, thus operate directly on the data in your data hub. In the following topics, learn how to use Rhize&amp;rsquo;s BPMN engine.</description></item><item><title>Upgrade</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/upgrade/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 15:02:24 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/deploy/upgrade/</guid><description>This guide shows you how to upgrade Rhize.
Prerequisites Before you start, ensure you have the following:
Access to the Rhize Kubernetes Environment helm Optional: kubectx utilities kubectx to manage multiple clusters kubens to switch between and configure namespaces easily Optional: the k8 Lens IDE, if you prefer to use Kubernetes graphically Be sure that you notify relevant parties of the coming upgrade.
Procedure First, record the old and new versions, their context, and namespaces.</description></item><item><title>Audit</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/audit/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 12:47:09 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/how-to/audit/</guid><description>The Audit Log provides a tamper-proof and immutable audit trail of all events that occur in the Rhize system. Users with appropriate permissions can access the audit log either through the UI menu or the GraphQL API.
Prerequisites To use the audit log, ensure you have the following:
If accessing to your Rhize UI environment, a user account with appropriate permissions
If accessing through GraphQL, you also need:
The ability to Use the Rhize GraphQL API A token configured so that audience includes audit, and the scopes contain audit:query.</description></item></channel></rss>