<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Restore on</title><link>https://libremfg.github.io/deploy/restore/</link><description>Recent content in Restore on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 19:35:35 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://libremfg.github.io/deploy/restore/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Restore the GraphDB</title><link>https://libremfg.github.io/deploy/restore/graphdb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 13:52:23 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://libremfg.github.io/deploy/restore/graphdb/</guid><description>This guide shows you how to restore the Graph database in your Rhize environment.
Prerequisites Before you start, ensure you have the following:
The GraphDB helm chart A Database backup kubectl Optional: kubectx utilities kubectx to manage multiple clusters kubens to switch between and configure namespaces easily Optional: the k8 Lens IDE, if you prefer to manage Kubernetes graphically Steps Confirm the cluster and namespace are correct.
## context kubectl config current-context ## namespace kubectl get namespace Copy the tar file into the new Grafana Pod within the /var/lib/grafana/ directory.</description></item><item><title>Restore Grafana</title><link>https://libremfg.github.io/deploy/restore/grafana/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 13:52:23 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://libremfg.github.io/deploy/restore/grafana/</guid><description>This guide shows you how to restore Grafana in your Rhize environment.
Prerequisites Before you start, ensure you have the following:
kubectl Optional: kubectx utilities kubectx to manage multiple clusters kubens to switch between and configure namespaces easily Optional: the k8 Lens IDE, if you prefer to manage Kubernetes graphically A Grafana backup Steps Confirm the cluster and namespace are correct.
## context kubectl config current-context ## namespace kubectl get namespace Copy the tar file into the new Grafana Pod within the /var/lib/grafana/ directory.</description></item><item><title>Restore InfluxDB</title><link>https://libremfg.github.io/deploy/restore/influxdb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 13:52:23 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://libremfg.github.io/deploy/restore/influxdb/</guid><description>This guide shows you how to restore InfluxDB in your Rhize environment.
Prerequisites Before you start, ensure you have the following:
kubectl Optional: kubectx utilities kubectx to manage multiple clusters kubens to switch between and configure namespaces easily Optional: the k8 Lens IDE, if you prefer to manage Kubernetes graphically An InfluxDB backup Steps Confirm the cluster and namespace are correct.
## context kubectl config current-context ## namespace kubectl get namespace Create a PersistentVolumeClaim for the InfluxDB backup file (adjust size as needed):</description></item></channel></rss>