<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Releases on</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/categories/releases/</link><description>Recent content in Releases on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 13:01:02 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.rhize.com/categories/releases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>3.0.0rc08</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/releases/3-0-0rc08/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 13:01:02 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/releases/3-0-0rc08/</guid><description>Release notes for version 3.0.0rc08 of the Rhize application.
Release date: 19th December, 2023
Breaking changes [ADMINUI] Change UI navigation bar design [SCHEMA] Change OperationsEventClass.IncludedIn to reference an OperationsEventClassVersion instead of OperationsEventClass [SCHEMA] Change OperationsEventClass.IncludesPropertiesOf to move to the version instance, OperationsEventClassVersion.IncludesPropertiesOf, instead of header [SCHEMA] Change OperationsEventDefinition.IncludedIn to reference an OperationsEventDefinitionVersion instead of OperationsEventDefinition [SCHEMA] Change OperationsEventDefinition.IncludesPropertiesOf to move to the version instance, OperationsEventDefinitionVersion.IncludesPropertiesOf, instead of header [SCHEMA] Change FromResourceReference and ToResourceReference to combine them into a single resourceReference Changes by service Admin UI Features</description></item><item><title>3.0.0rc07</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/releases/3-0-0rc07/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 09:32:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/releases/3-0-0rc07/</guid><description>Release notes for version 3.0.0rc07 of the Rhize application.
Release date: 15th November, 2023
Breaking changes [SCHEMA] Change types OperationalLocationClass, OperationalLocationClassVersion, OperationalLocationClassProperty, OperationalLocation, OperationalLocationVersion and OperationalLocationProperty to have: isPartOf (0..1), isMadeUpOf (0..*) [BPMN] Change CommandConsumer and Timers to use new JetStream library and durable consumers. This requires you to drop and re-create streams KV_JobResponses, KV_WorkflowSpecifications, libreBpmn_Command and libreTimerStart. Changes by service Admin UI Features
Add ability to create Process Segment Version Add ability to edit linked process segment resource specification property Add ability to link a Hierarchy Scope to a Operational Location Class version Add check for renaming a linked property with an existing property name Add Homepage screen Add optional link from Operational Location Class to a Operational Location Class version Add Physical Asset Properties Add Physical Asset Resource Specifications Change</description></item><item><title>3.0.0rc06</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/releases/3-0-0rc06/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 21:07:43 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/releases/3-0-0rc06/</guid><description>Release notes for version 3.0.0rc06 of the Rhize application.
Release date: October 31, 2023
Breaking changes NATS streams libreBpmn_command and LibreTimerStart must be deleted prior to starting Changes by service Core Features
Add mutation for dependency check for DataSource, Equipment, EquipmentClass, OperationalLocation, and OperationalLocationClass Changes
Change to go-module for schema Change struct literal unkeyed fields to keyed BPMN Breaking Changes
NATS streams libreBpmn_command and LibreTimerStart must be deleted prior to starting Features</description></item><item><title>3.0.0rc05</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/releases/3-0-0rc05/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 20:32:34 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/releases/3-0-0rc05/</guid><description>Release notes for version 3.0.0rc05 of the Rhize application.
Release date: October 24, 2023
Breaking changes Renamed UI environment variables and changed KEYCLOACK to KEYCLOAK Changes by service Core Features
Add deleteSyncEquipmentsFromDBtoNATSStatus mutation Add NATS connection name Add fields to InformationObject Fixes
Fix tracing typo Changes
Change Core to purge keys that are not in the the database Change core to delete property value from KV when the equipment no longer have active version BPMN Features</description></item></channel></rss>