<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Howto on Rhize documentation</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/categories/howto/</link><description>Recent content in Howto on Rhize documentation</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://docs.rhize.com/categories/howto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Genealogy</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/use-cases/genealogy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/use-cases/genealogy/</guid><description>This document provides a high-level overview of how to use Rhize for use cases in material genealogy.
In manufacturing, a genealogy is the record of what a material contains or what it is now a part of. As its name implies, genealogy represents the family tree of the material. A material genealogy can help manufacturers in multiple ways:
Prevent product recalls by isolating deviations early in the material flow Decrease recall time by having a complete record of where material starts and ends Help build reports and analysis of material deviations To create documentation and compliance records for material tracking Rhize provides a standards-based schema to represent material in at all levels of granularity.</description></item><item><title>Electronic batch records</title><link>https://docs.rhize.com/use-cases/ebr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.rhize.com/use-cases/ebr/</guid><description>In pharmaceutical manufacturing, an Electronic Batch Record (eBR) is a detailed report about a specific batch. It includes information about items such as the process segments, material, personnel, and equipment.
As Rhize can ingest data from all levels of the manufacturing process, and do so in real-time, it is an ideal single source of truth to create eBRs. The process can be automated and highly efficient. Our experience in production systems shows that Rhize can typically generate an eBR in less than 500 milliseconds.</description></item></channel></rss>