<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Enterprise Features on</title><link>/enterprise-features/</link><description>Recent content in Enterprise Features on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 19:35:35 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/enterprise-features/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Audit Logging</title><link>/enterprise-features/audit-logs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 22:25:17 +1100</pubDate><guid>/enterprise-features/audit-logs/</guid><description>As a database administrator, you count on being able to audit access to your database. With a Dgraph enterprise license, you can enable audit logging so that all requests are tracked and available for use in security audits. When audit logging is enabled, the following information is recorded about the queries and mutations (requests) sent to your database:
Endpoint Logged-in User Name Server host address Client Host address Request Body (truncated at 4KB) Timestamp Namespace Query Parameters (if provided) Response status Audit log scope Most queries and mutations sent to Dgraph Alpha and Dgraph Zero are logged.</description></item><item><title>Backup List Tool</title><link>/enterprise-features/lsbackup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 22:25:17 +1100</pubDate><guid>/enterprise-features/lsbackup/</guid><description>The lsbackup command-line tool prints information about the stored backups in a user-defined location.
Parameters The lsbackup command has two flags:
Flags: -h, --help help for lsbackup -l, --location string Sets the source location URI (required). --verbose Outputs additional info in backup list. --location: indicates a source URI with Dgraph backup objects. This URI supports all the schemes used for backup. --verbose: if enabled will print additional information about the selected backup.</description></item><item><title>Binary Backups</title><link>/enterprise-features/binary-backups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 22:25:17 +1100</pubDate><guid>/enterprise-features/binary-backups/</guid><description>Note This feature was introduced in v1.1.0. Binary backups are full backups of Dgraph that are backed up directly to cloud storage such as Amazon S3 or any Minio storage backend. Backups can also be saved to an on-premise network file system shared by all Alpha servers. These backups can be used to restore a new Dgraph cluster to the previous state from the backup. Unlike exports, binary backups are Dgraph-specific and can be used to restore a cluster quickly.</description></item><item><title>Encryption at Rest</title><link>/enterprise-features/encryption-at-rest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 22:25:17 +1100</pubDate><guid>/enterprise-features/encryption-at-rest/</guid><description>Note This feature was introduced in v1.1.1. For migrating unencrypted data to a new Dgraph cluster with encryption enabled, you need to export the database and fast data load, preferably using the bulk loader. Encryption at rest refers to the encryption of data that is stored physically in any digital form. It ensures that sensitive data on disks is not readable by any user or application without a valid key that is required for decryption.</description></item><item><title>Learner Nodes</title><link>/enterprise-features/learner-nodes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 22:25:17 +1100</pubDate><guid>/enterprise-features/learner-nodes/</guid><description>A Learner node is an enterprise-only feature that allows a user to spin-up a read-only replica instance across the world without paying a latency cost. When enabled, a Dgraph cluster using learner nodes can serve best-effort queries faster.
A &amp;ldquo;learner node&amp;rdquo; can still accept write operations. The node forwards them over to the Alpha group leader and does the writing just like a typical Alpha node. It will just be slower, depending on the latency between the Alpha node and the learner node.</description></item><item><title>License</title><link>/enterprise-features/license/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 22:25:17 +1100</pubDate><guid>/enterprise-features/license/</guid><description>Dgraph enterprise features are enabled by default for 30 days in a new cluster. After the trial period of thirty (30) days, the cluster must obtain a license from Dgraph to continue using the enterprise features released in the proprietary code.
Note At the conclusion of your 30-day trial period if a license has not been applied to the cluster, access to the enterprise features will be suspended. The cluster will continue to operate without enterprise features.</description></item></channel></rss>